{
  "title": "2.5",
  "definitions": {
    "WAIL": {
      "word": "WAIL",
      "phonetic": "(wail)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cry, weep </p><p>To WAIL is to cry, usually long and loud in a voice that expresses deep unhappiness or pain; to make a loud, high-pitched sound. </p><p>“The baby WAILED when we took her bottle away.” </p><p>“We could hear the siren WAIL in the distance.” </p><p>WAIL is also a noun. </p><p>“Jane gave out a loud WAIL when she saw that everyone had left without her.”</p>"
    },
    "ABSURD": {
      "word": "ABSURD",
      "phonetic": "(gb-serd'",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">ridiculous, foolish, unreasonable </p><p>Something that is ABSURD makes no sense; it is not reasonable. </p><p>“It was freezing outside when he made the ABSURD suggestion that we all go swimming.” </p><p>“You may think the plan is reasonable, but I consider it ABSURD.” </p><p>“The television show was completely ABSURD. I’ve never seen a sillier program.” </p><p>The noun from ABSURD is ABSURDITY, which means <i class=“def-ital\">ridiculousness</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">foolishness</i>. </p><p>“She understands the ABSURDITY of pretending to be richer than she is.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ABSURDITY, n.</p>"
    },
    "DEVOUR": {
      "word": "DEVOUR",
      "phonetic": "(di-vowr')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to eat, eat up, consume </p><p>To DEVOUR something is to eat it up greedily. </p><p>“He was so hungry that he DEVOURED the entire pizza at once.” </p><p>DEVOUR can also mean “to use up as if by eating greedily.” </p><p>“The raging fire DEVOURED an entire city block.” </p><p>“He liked her writing so much that he DEVOURED each book in one sitting\"—that is, he read each one quickly and eagerly.</p>"
    },
    "CEASE": {
      "word": "CEASE",
      "phonetic": "(sEs)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to stop, halt, end </p><p>To CEASE is to <i class=“def-ital\">stop</i>, to bring or come to an end. </p><p>“The teacher told them to CEASE talking.” </p><p>“When the rain CEASED the children came out to play again.” </p><p>“Their club CEASED to exist many years ago.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CEASELESS, adj.</p>"
    },
    "ELIGIBLE": {
      "word": "ELIGIBLE",
      "phonetic": "(el'-ÔøΩjÔøΩbgl)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">fit to be chosen, desirable; qualified </p><p> ELIGIBLE comes from the same Latin word as <i class=“def-ital\">elect</i>; both words have to do with choosing. To <i class=“def-ital\">elect</i> is to <i class=“def-ital\">choose</i>, particularly to choose someone for public office. An ELIGIBLE person is fit or qualified to be chosen. Sometimes this means the person has satisfied legal or other requirements: if you are “ELIGIBLE for football,” it means, usually, that your school grades are high enough for you to be allowed to play on a team. </p><p>“Previous winners are not ELIGIBLE to enter the contest again.” </p><p>Sometimes ELIGIBLE simply means “fit to be chosen” because the person or thing is good or desirable: “ELIGIBLE bachelors” are single men who are suitable or desirable for marriage. </p><p>Other forms of the word: ELIGIBILITY, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-able</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "AMATEUR": {
      "word": "AMATEUR",
      "phonetic": "(am'-g-cher",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">nonprofessional </p><p>AMATEUR means <i class=“def-ital\">not professional</i>, that is, “not paid for what is being done.” AMATEUR comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">love</i>, and is used about people who do something for the love of it, or as a pastime, not to earn money. </p><p>“He was an AMATEUR tennis player; he never played the game for money.” </p><p>“We enjoyed the AMATEUR production of <i class=“def-ital\">Romeo and Juliet</i>.” </p><p>AMATEUR can also be used as a noun and means “a person who does something for the love of it or as a pastime.” </p><p>“Many AMATEURS eventually become professionals.” </p><p>AMATEUR often, but not always, suggests that the person is inexperienced and not very good at what he is doing. </p><p>“He’s just an AMATEUR at this. He’s only been doing it for a couple of months.” </p><p>“She has become such a great pianist that we can no longer call her an AMATEUR.”</p>"
    },
    "EXCLUDE": {
      "word": "EXCLUDE",
      "phonetic": "(eks-klUd')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to keep out, bar, leave out </p><p> EXCLUDE means to <i class=“def-ital\">shut out</i>, to keep someone or something from getting in. You can EXCLUDE either persons or things. </p><p>“Everyone agreed we had to EXCLUDE him from the club.” </p><p>“They decided their report would EXCLUDE all mention of the incident.” </p><p>“We can EXCLUDE the possibility that you committed the crime, since you were out of the country at the time.” </p><p>The adjective from EXCLUDE is EXCLUSIVE. EXCLUSIVE stores deal only with certain rich customers. An EXCLUSIVE in a newspaper is a piece of news which only that newspaper has uncovered, and which it prints before anyone else. </p><p>Other forms of the word: EXCLUSION, n. </p><p>EXCLUSIVE, adj., n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "HOIST": {
      "word": "HOIST",
      "phonetic": "(hoyst)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to raise, lift </p><p>HOIST means to <i class=“def-ital\">lift</i>. The word is especially used about lifting something very heavy by mechanical means. </p><p>“They HOISTED the boat out of the water with ropes and pulleys.” </p><p>“The movers had difficulty HOISTING the piano up to the third floor.” </p><p>HOIST can also be used as a noun and means “a device for lifting.” </p><p>“They used the HOIST to lift the engine out of the car.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">steal</i>. This is probably due to a confusion of HOIST with <i class=“def-ital\">heist</i>, which means a <i class=“def-ital\">robbery</i>.</p>"
    },
    "IMPERSONATE": {
      "word": "IMPERSONATE",
      "phonetic": "(im-per'-sÔøΩn-At)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to pretend to be, act the part of </p><p>To IMPERSONATE someone is to pretend you are that person, to act his part. </p><p>“The robber got into the apartment by IMPERSONATING a telephone repairman.” </p><p>“She IMPERSONATED the movie star so well it was hard to believe she was only a waitress.” </p><p>The noun from IMPERSONATE is IMPERSONATION. </p><p>“His clever IMPERSONATION fooled everyone.” </p><p>Many people think that to IMPERSONATE someone is to <i class=“def-ital\">make fun of</i> him. But you can pretend to be a person without making fun of him. </p><p>Other forms of the word: IMPERSONATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "EXPOSE": {
      "word": "EXPOSE",
      "phonetic": "(eks-pOz')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to uncover, leave open; to disclose, make known </p><p>To EXPOSE is to put out in the open what has previously been protected, hidden, or secret. EXPOSE can be used about physical objects and people. </p><p>“The statue was EXPOSED to the wind and the rain.” </p><p>“The destruction of the fort EXPOSED the soldiers to enemy gunfire.” </p><p>EXPOSE can also be used about plots and secrets. </p><p>“The reporter EXPOSED the secret plot to overthrow the government.” </p><p>EXPOSURE is a noun form of EXPOSE. To die of EXPOSURE means to die from being outside in the cold or the heat for too long. </p><p>“The EXPOSURE of his crimes shocked everyone.” </p><p>“Too much EXPOSURE to X-rays is dangerous.” </p><p>” Other forms of the word: EXPOSURE, n.</p>"
    },
    "KERNEL": {
      "word": "KERNEL",
      "phonetic": "(ker'-nÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a seed, core, central part </p><p>A KERNEL is the soft inner part of a nut or a fruit stone. It is also the whole grain or seed of a cereal like wheat or corn. </p><p>“The KERNELS of corn were cut from the ears and put into cans.” </p><p>In general use, KERNEL means “the central or most important part of something.” </p><p>“Although I disagree with much of what you say, there is a KERNEL of truth in it\"—that is, an important, essential part of it is true.</p>"
    },
    "LEASE": {
      "word": "LEASE",
      "phonetic": "(IEs)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to rent </p><p>A LEASE is a contract renting lands, buildings, or the like to someone for a certain period of time. To LEASE something is to rent it to or from someone. </p><p>“He LEASED the farm from its owner for ten years.” </p><p>“The man LEASED the automobile to us for six months.” </p><p>The most common mistake on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">sell</i>. To LEASE something involves paying money for the use of it for a certain period of time. But it does not involve buying or selling.</p>"
    },
    "PENITENTIARY": {
      "word": "PENITENTIARY",
      "phonetic": "(pen-J-ten'-shJ-rE)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a prison, reformatory </p><p>PENITENTIARY is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">penitent</i>, which means <i class=“def-ital\">sorry</i>. A PENITENTIARY is a place where people are sent as punishment for crimes they have committed. In the US, a PENITENTIARY is always a state or federal prison for people who have committed serious crimes. </p><p>“He entered the PENITENTIARY to begin his five-year sentence for robbery.” </p><p>“He worked as a guard in the state’s largest PENITENTIARY.”</p>"
    },
    "ACCELERATE": {
      "word": "ACCELERATE",
      "phonetic": "(ak-sel'-ÔøΩ-rAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to speed up, hasten, go faster </p><p>To ACCELERATE something is to make it go faster, to speed it up. </p><p>“Fertilizer ACCELERATES the growth of most plants.” </p><p>“The regular program takes six months; the ACCELERATED program takes only three months.” </p><p>When something ACCELERATES, it speeds up. </p><p>“The car ACCELERATED to sixty miles an hour very quickly.” </p><p>In a car, the ACCELERATOR, or gas pedal, controls the car’s speed. </p><p>“He pressed down on the ACCELERATOR in order to pass the car in front of him.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ACCELERATION, n., ACCELERATOR, n.</p>"
    },
    "PRECISE": {
      "word": "PRECISE",
      "phonetic": "(pri-sls')",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">exact, certain, correct </p><p>PRECISE means <i class=“def-ital\">exact</i>, “without error or unclearness.” </p><p>“He says he’ll come some time next week, but he can’t be more PRECISE than that.” </p><p>“Donna tried to be PRECISE in her description of the car.” </p><p>“The bank knew the PRECISE amount of money he had in his savings account.” </p><p>“The game will start at PRECISELY eight o’clock—not a minute sooner or later.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PRECISION, n.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "5",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Began to WAIL.",
          "answers": [
            "laugh",
            "run",
            "fight",
            "hurt",
            "cry"
          ],
          "word": "WAIL",
          "correct": "cry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ABSURD plan.",
          "answers": [
            "helpful",
            "fake",
            "ridiculous",
            "clever",
            "humorous"
          ],
          "word": "ABSURD",
          "correct": "ridiculous"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEVOURED the cake.",
          "answers": [
            "baked",
            "ate",
            "tasted",
            "burned",
            "passed"
          ],
          "word": "DEVOUR",
          "correct": "ate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You must CEASE.",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "slow down",
            "change",
            "begin",
            "continue"
          ],
          "word": "CEASE",
          "correct": "stop"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were ELIGIBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "reliable",
            "beautiful",
            "qualified",
            "successful",
            "poor"
          ],
          "word": "ELIGIBLE",
          "correct": "qualified"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AMATEUR athlete.",
          "answers": [
            "stupid",
            "college",
            "nonprofessional",
            "paid",
            "young"
          ],
          "word": "AMATEUR",
          "correct": "nonprofessional"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They EXCLUDE all foreigners.",
          "answers": [
            "hate",
            "disapprove of",
            "keep out",
            "welcome",
            "hide"
          ],
          "word": "EXCLUDE",
          "correct": "keep out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to HOIST it.",
          "answers": [
            "carry",
            "steal",
            "watch",
            "raise",
            "lower"
          ],
          "word": "HOIST",
          "correct": "raise"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMPERSONATE him.",
          "answers": [
            "meet",
            "make fun of",
            "beg",
            "imitate",
            "kill"
          ],
          "word": "IMPERSONATE",
          "correct": "imitate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They EXPOSED it.",
          "answers": [
            "uncovered",
            "talked about",
            "saw",
            "guessed",
            "overlooked"
          ],
          "word": "EXPOSE",
          "correct": "uncovered"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Found the KERNEL.",
          "answers": [
            "root",
            "top",
            "skin",
            "seed",
            "weed"
          ],
          "word": "KERNEL",
          "correct": "seed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He LEASED it.",
          "answers": [
            "saved",
            "rented",
            "bought",
            "lost",
            "sold"
          ],
          "word": "LEASE",
          "correct": "rented"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Entered the PENITENTIARY.",
          "answers": [
            "church",
            "cell",
            "school",
            "prison",
            "court"
          ],
          "word": "PENITENTIARY",
          "correct": "prison"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The car ACCELERATES.",
          "answers": [
            "races",
            "improves",
            "crashes",
            "slows down",
            "speeds up"
          ],
          "word": "ACCELERATE",
          "correct": "speeds up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The PRECISE meaning.",
          "answers": [
            "former",
            "exact",
            "greatest",
            "usual",
            "general"
          ],
          "word": "PRECISE",
          "correct": "exact"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do people generally WAIL when they are happy?",
          "word": "WAIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it ABSURD to ask for help when you're in trouble?",
          "word": "ABSURD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a hungry dog DEVOUR a piece of meat?",
          "word": "DEVOUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Will you get thin if you CEASE eating?",
          "word": "CEASE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are children ELIGIBLE to vote for president?",
          "word": "ELIGIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are major league baseball players AMATEURS?",
          "word": "AMATEUR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an EXCLUSIVE club let in everyone who wanted to join it?",
          "word": "EXCLUDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be easy for one person to HOIST an airplane?",
          "word": "HOIST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be easy for identical twins to IMPERSONATE each other?",
          "word": "IMPERSONATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can EXPOSURE to the hot sun give you sunburn?",
          "word": "EXPOSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a corn KERNEL be very large?",
          "word": "KERNEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can automobiles be LEASED?",
          "word": "LEASE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually dislike being in a PENITENTIARY?",
          "word": "PENITENTIARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a car ACCELERATE when it hits a brick wall?",
          "word": "ACCELERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is \"sometime next year\" a PRECISE time?",
          "word": "PRECISE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone in the building could hear her WAILING over the death of her friend.",
          "word": "WAIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I'm not in the mood for foolishness, so don't give me any ABSURD explanations.",
          "word": "ABSURD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She DEVOURED the table so that it was completely clean.",
          "word": "DEVOUR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After listening to the same song for two hours, he was glad when it CEASED.",
          "word": "CEASE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The chair is so ELIGIBLE it will fall apart when someone sits in it.",
          "word": "ELIGIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He enjoyed being an AMATEUR chess player and didn't care whether or not he made any money at it.",
          "word": "AMATEUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Walter was EXCLUDED from taking part because he was too young.",
          "word": "EXCLUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The golfer HOISTED the ball into the hole.",
          "word": "HOIST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Sally can do a great IMPERSONATION of her aunt.",
          "word": "IMPERSONATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Our digging EXPOSED some ancient statues that had been buried for centuries.",
          "word": "EXPOSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There wasn't a KERNEL of truth to the rumor that the teacher was quitting.",
          "word": "KERNEL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mr. Allen makes a good income by LEASING apartments he owns.",
          "word": "LEASE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The judge sentenced him to ten years in the PENITENTIARY.",
          "word": "PENITENTIARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They told us we were going too fast and should ACCELERATE our pace instead.",
          "word": "ACCELERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The PRECISE value of the painting is from two to ten thousand dollars or so.",
          "word": "PRECISE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "WAIL",
          "answers": [
            "yell",
            "sob",
            "chat"
          ],
          "word": "WAIL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABSURD",
          "answers": [
            "unsafe",
            "foolish",
            "senseless"
          ],
          "word": "ABSURD",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEVOUR",
          "answers": [
            "give up",
            "use up",
            "eat"
          ],
          "word": "DEVOUR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CEASE",
          "answers": [
            "end",
            "wait",
            "quit"
          ],
          "word": "CEASE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELIGIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "eager",
            "suitable",
            "desirable"
          ],
          "word": "ELIGIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AMATEUR",
          "answers": [
            "unusual",
            "unpaid",
            "inexperienced"
          ],
          "word": "AMATEUR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXCLUDE",
          "answers": [
            "enter",
            "omit",
            "leave out"
          ],
          "word": "EXCLUDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HOIST",
          "answers": [
            "raise",
            "carry",
            "lift"
          ],
          "word": "HOIST",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMPERSONATE",
          "answers": [
            "imitate",
            "imagine",
            "pretend"
          ],
          "word": "IMPERSONATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXPOSE",
          "answers": [
            "renew",
            "open",
            "bare"
          ],
          "word": "EXPOSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "KERNEL",
          "answers": [
            "end",
            "seed",
            "center"
          ],
          "word": "KERNEL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEASE",
          "answers": [
            "rent",
            "give",
            "use"
          ],
          "word": "LEASE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PENITENTIARY",
          "answers": [
            "whip",
            "jail",
            "prison"
          ],
          "word": "PENITENTIARY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACCELERATE",
          "answers": [
            "quicken",
            "enlarge",
            "hasten"
          ],
          "word": "ACCELERATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRECISE",
          "answers": [
            "true",
            "correct",
            "usual"
          ],
          "word": "PRECISE",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}